# **Francis Victa**

## Data Analyst / Software Developer

A solution-oriented Data Analyst with significant experience in applying data analysis in various fields. Motivated and driven by the desire to make an impact to the world. Passionate about technology, and embraces the challenges of working as an analyst. Not afraid to fail, and will go the extra mile to achieve greater things.

York, ON M9N 0B1

□ 416-832-1771



<u>linkedin.com/in/francisvicta</u> <u>victafrancis.github.io/portfolio/</u>

## SUMMARY OF EXPERIENCE

- √ 3+ years of experience as a data analyst
- √ 3+ years of programming experience (including software and web development)
- ✓ 2+ years of experience in customer technical support

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- ✓ Data Analysis and Machine Learning: Python, Numpy, Pandas, Scikit-Learn, Keras, SQL, NoSQL, Tableau, Excel, Access
- ✓ Programming and Web Development Tools: Java, C#, Python, JavaScript, PHP, HTML5, Bootstrap, Node.is, React, AngularJS, Typescript, ASP.NET, Android Studio, VBA for Excel, Postman, RESTful API
- ✓ General: Git Version Control and MS Office Suite

#### **RELEVANT PROJECTS**

- Coronavirus Digital Agent (Python, Keras, Flask, Pandas, Numpy)
  - A digital agent that answers questions about the Coronavirus
  - Trained by a Densely Connected Neural Network
  - Use BeautifulSoup to update the site with current global data
- College Application Regression and Classification (Python, scikit-learn, Pandas, Keras)
  - Used various supervised learning models such as Linear Regression, Logistic Regression, KNN, SVM and Decision Tree Classifiers to predict outcomes
  - Pandas and MS Excel used for data preparation
  - Matplotlib used for data visualization
- Capstone Project: Gym Information and Tracking System (MEAN stack)
  - Developed a full-stack (front-end UI, back-end server, database) web application that manages data and information within a business entity (CRUD functionalities)
  - o Mainly worked on developing back-end APIs using NodeJS to access MonggoDB collections
- GPS Route Tracker (Java, Android Studio, SQLite)
  - Developed an android application that tracks a route taken using GPS and draws it to a google map API
- Art Database Management System (PHP, MySQL, Apache)
  - Simple CRUD application for managing an Art Database
- Casino game (JavaScript, HTML, CSS)
  - Used mathematical probabilities and basic casino game mechanics
- Memory Sequence game (JavaScript, HTML, CSS)
  - Game to improve individual short-term memory

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Computer Programmer Analyst (Advanced Diploma)**

George Brown College, Toronto, ON Dean's List (Cumulative GPA: **3.98**)

## **Bachelor of Science in Management Engineering (Honours Program)**

2008 - 2012

2018 - Expected 2020

Ateneo de Manila University, Manila, Philippines (WES accredited, Top Philippine University) Financial Aid Scholar

Dean's List

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Marketing Database Support

2019 - Expected April 2020

## **George Brown College, Toronto**

- Prepared/Cleaned marketing data and liaised with the team to carry out suitable analysis
- Designed and automated dashboards with data visualizations to deliver key department insights using MS Access and Tableau which reduced manual work by 75%
- Created SQL scripts to extract and manipulate data from database to meet client's requests
- Used machine learning models (Python, Pandas, SkLearn) to discover and predict which marketing events led to more applications

## Project Analyst/Tier-1 Technical Support

2015-2017

## [24]7.ai, Toronto

- Prepared daily client reports which included analysis of trends and performance data
- Designed and developed workflow macros (using Visual Basic for Excel) which increased overall team
  efficiency by at least 50%, measured by work hours logged per project per employee (This saved the
  company a lot of time and money)
- Created numerous internal and external client reporting templates which replaced the older and outdated versions
- Handled level 1 client issues over the phone; created escalation tickets for level 2 client tech support
- Recipient of quarterly Bravo Award for showing great performance and leadership in developing and implementing process improvement methods
- Provided MS Excel training workshops to peers

#### Production Operator/Production Specialist

2013-2015

## Woodbridge Foam Corporation, Woodbridge, Vaughan

- Sorted complex data, created data spreadsheets, prepared reports, and organized files and records
- Improved the production line scheduling process by designing an application in MS Excel which improved efficiency of production line by more than 10% (measured in reduction of product line cancellations)
- Created spreadsheet to monitor Work in Process Inventory products running on schedule

## Floor/Backroom Associate

January – June 2013

## Target Canada, Brampton Shopper's World

- Worked with Target's in-house software systems, updating merchandise inventory, etc.
- Analyzed and organized the backroom to be able to efficiently work with the whole system of pulling and pushing merchandise on the sales floor
- Recipient of "Team Member of the Month" award

#### **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

UofT Hacks 2019 Volunteer, University of Toronto, Toronto

January 2019

- Coordinated with representatives from Microsoft, Google, etc. to help set up sponsor booths
- Manned booths and supported the hackers on their hackathon guest